<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Application</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="when_there_is_an_infection_of_any_sort_be_it_bacterial_viral_or_parasitic_fever_is_a_natural_response_to_it_from_within_it_is_often_noticed_when_there_is_a_rise_in_body_temperature_and_related_uneasiness_like_muscle_ache_fatigue_or_feeling_cold_the_natural_body_temperature_ranges_from_99_5_f_to_100_9_f_or_between_37_5_c_to_38_3_c_when_there_is_fever_there_is_a_spike_in_body_temperature_and_this_is_one_of_the_common_indicators_of_the_same_with_minute_differences_based_on_the_body_type_it_is_highly_recommended_to_consult_a_doctor_if_the_fever_persists_for_more_than_3_days_nevertheless_ayurvedic_doctors_suggest_a_few_home_remedies_that_can_bring_down_the_temperature_and_help_reduce_the_fever_1_garlic_garlic_can_promote_sweating_which_in_turn_flushes_out_toxins_from_the_body_effectively_garlic_is_usually_used_in_everyday_cooking_in_most_households_and_there_are_multiple_ways_of_using_garlic_to_stay_healthy_as_part_of_everyday_meals_the_first_way_to_use_garlic_is_by_crushing_the_cloves_mixing_them_up_with_oil_in_the_household_and_applying_the_mixture_on_the_feet_this_can_be_applied_during_the_night_before_going_to_sleep_and_there_would_be_a_considerable_difference_by_morning_the_second_way_to_use_garlic_is_by_drinking_it_a_simple_mixture_can_be_prepared_by_finely_mincing_garlic_and_adding_it_to_warm_water_you_can_let_the_garlic_stay_in_for_a_few_minutes_in_the_concoction_before_you_drink_it_up_it_can_be_consumed_up_to_two_times_a_day_garlic_has_antibacterial_and_antiviral_properties_other_than_the_several_other_health_benefits_it_possesses_2_basil_basic_is_usually_grown_in_every_indian_household_and_is_highly_accessible_basil_tea_is_one_of_the_most_common_home_remedies_for_fever_add_basil_to_boiling_water_and_crush_a_little_ginger_with_it_once_the_concoction_feels_stronger_it_can_be_poured_to_the_cup_with_a_little_honey_to_add_taste_to_it">When there is an infection of any sort, be it bacterial, viral or parasitic, fever is a natural response to it from within. It is often noticed when there is a rise in body temperature and related uneasiness like muscle ache, fatigue or feeling cold. The natural body temperature ranges from 99.5째F to 100.9째F or between 37.5째C to 38.3째C. When there is fever, there is a spike in body temperature and this is one of the common indicators of the same, with minute differences based on the body type. It is highly recommended to consult a doctor if the fever persists for more than 3 days. Nevertheless, Ayurvedic doctors suggest a few home remedies that can bring down the temperature and help reduce the fever. 1.Garlic Garlic can promote sweating, which in turn flushes out toxins from the body effectively. Garlic is usually used in everyday cooking in most households and there are multiple ways of using garlic to stay healthy, as part of everyday meals. The first way to use garlic is by crushing the cloves, mixing them up with oil in the household and applying the mixture on the feet. This can be applied during the night before going to sleep and there would be a considerable difference by morning. The second way to use garlic is by drinking it. A simple mixture can be prepared by finely mincing garlic and adding it to warm water. You can let the garlic stay in for a few minutes in the concoction before you drink it up. It can be consumed up to two times a day. Garlic has antibacterial and antiviral properties other than the several other health benefits it possesses. 2. Basil Basic is usually grown in every Indian household and is highly accessible. Basil tea is one of the most common home remedies for fever. Add basil to boiling water and crush a little ginger with it. Once the concoction feels stronger, it can be poured to the cup with a little honey to add taste to it.</string>
    <string name="diabetes_is_a_chronic_condition_that_affects_how_the_body_processes_blood_sugar_glucose_here_are_some_tips_for_controlling_diabetes_monitor_blood_sugar_monitoring_blood_sugar_levels_regularly_is_critical_for_managing_diabetes_keeping_a_log_of_blood_sugar_readings_can_help_individuals_identify_patterns_and_make_adjustments_to_their_diabetes_management_plan_as_needed_follow_a_healthy_diet_eating_a_healthy_diet_is_essential_for_managing_diabetes_a_balanced_diet_that_includes_whole_grains_fruits_vegetables_lean_protein_and_healthy_fats_can_help_regulate_blood_sugar_levels_and_reduce_the_risk_of_complications_exercise_regularly_regular_exercise_can_help_manage_diabetes_by_improving_insulin_sensitivity_and_regulating_blood_sugar_levels_aim_for_at_least_30_minutes_of_moderate_intensity_exercise_most_days_of_the_week_take_medications_as_prescribed_many_people_with_diabetes_require_medication_to_manage_their_blood_sugar_levels_it_is_essential_to_take_medications_as_prescribed_by_a_healthcare_provider_to_maintain_optimal_blood_sugar_control_manage_stress_stress_can_raise_blood_sugar_levels_and_make_diabetes_management_more_challenging_managing_stress_through_relaxation_techniques_such_as_yoga_meditation_or_deep_breathing_can_help_individuals_manage_their_diabetes_more_effectively_maintain_a_healthy_weight_maintaining_a_healthy_weight_is_essential_for_managing_diabetes_excess_body_weight_can_make_it_more_challenging_to_control_blood_sugar_levels_and_increase_the_risk_of_complications_get_regular_check_ups_regular_check_ups_with_a_healthcare_provider_can_help_individuals_with_diabetes_manage_their_condition_effectively_healthcare_providers_can_provide_guidance_on_diabetes_management_monitor_blood_sugar_levels_and_adjust_treatment_plans_as_needed_overall_managing_diabetes_requires_a_comprehensive_approach_that_includes_diet_exercise_medication_and_stress_management_by_following_these_tips_individuals_with_diabetes_can_manage_their_condition_effectively_and_reduce_the_risk_of_complications">Diabetes is a chronic condition that affects how the body processes blood sugar (glucose). Here are some tips for controlling diabetes: Monitor Blood Sugar: Monitoring blood sugar levels regularly is critical for managing diabetes. Keeping a log of blood sugar readings can help individuals identify patterns and make adjustments to their diabetes management plan as needed. Follow a Healthy Diet: Eating a healthy diet is essential for managing diabetes. A balanced diet that includes whole grains, fruits, vegetables, lean protein, and healthy fats can help regulate blood sugar levels and reduce the risk of complications. Exercise Regularly: Regular exercise can help manage diabetes by improving insulin sensitivity and regulating blood sugar levels. Aim for at least 30 minutes of moderate-intensity exercise most days of the week. Take Medications as Prescribed: Many people with diabetes require medication to manage their blood sugar levels. It is essential to take medications as prescribed by a healthcare provider to maintain optimal blood sugar control. Manage Stress: Stress can raise blood sugar levels and make diabetes management more challenging. Managing stress through relaxation techniques such as yoga, meditation, or deep breathing can help individuals manage their diabetes more effectively. Maintain a Healthy Weight: Maintaining a healthy weight is essential for managing diabetes. Excess body weight can make it more challenging to control blood sugar levels and increase the risk of complications. Get Regular Check-Ups: Regular check-ups with a healthcare provider can help individuals with diabetes manage their condition effectively. Healthcare providers can provide guidance on diabetes management, monitor blood sugar levels, and adjust treatment plans as needed. Overall, managing diabetes requires a comprehensive approach that includes diet, exercise, medication, and stress management. By following these tips, individuals with diabetes can manage their condition effectively and reduce the risk of complications.</string>
    <string name="Ayurveda" />
</resources>